Khanh Nguyen

CAREER SUMMARY

Professional in Software Engineering with 5 years experience in various kinds of Project such as Windows Applications , Web Applications and recently move up to the Cloud Based-Applications. 4 out of 5 years experience with the Japanese companies and Japanese culture. Hard-work, dedicated and artisans in Software Engineering, Bilingual (Japanese and English) as well as native in Vienamese (a well-known Outsourcing Development Country). I am looking for opportunities in the Cloud Based-Web Application as well as Full Stack Development. 5 years working in multicultural environment and loving to be part of an international teams and join my hand in innovative projects where creativity and productivity are the core values. I'm available for hire now, drop me a messages if you are interested in.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Languages: PHP, JavaScript, .NET, Java

Technologies: Cloud Computing (AWS), Virtualization

Framework/Tools: Laravel, Cake PHP, Symfony, Entity Framework, LAMP Stack, Eclipse

Jenkins, Ansible

Database: MySQL, Aurora, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Centos, Ubuntu, Window Server

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VietIS Japan, Tokyo, Japan

2017/11 - Present

Bridge Software Engineer (full-time)

- Work as a technical leader to propose solution end-user
 - Perform code-review, assure the quality of offshore development center (based in Vietnam)
- Working on new Integration, Deployment process to automated the workflow and reduced the leakage in the system

Cloudpack, Tokyo, Japan

2016/04 - 2017/11

Bridge Software Engineer / Web Application Engineer (full-time)

- Web Development with PHP, Laravel Frameworks, based on Cloud Infrastructure, focusing on Availability, Accessibility, Scalability, Durability web applications
- Deploy Web Applications to Cloud and develop autonomated CI tasks.
- Use my communications skill to act as a "bridge" between Japanese colleagues and Offshore Development center in Vietnam.

Accomplishments

- Become a DevOps of one of the biggest Golf Reservations System in Japan
- Get certificated by AWS as an Associate Solutions Architect and several internal cloud-related certifications
- Always keep up with the latest technologies both in Cloud Computing and Web
 Applications and applied them to current project such as Vue.js, Progressive Web Apps...
 to deliver the most excellent Application to customers.

FPT Information Systems, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2013/10 - 2016/3

Bridge Software Engineer (full-time)

- Maintain and Operate chemistry Sales and Delivery Systems (written in VB.NET). Act as a Bridge between Japanese IT Help Desk and Thailand IT Helpdesk to resolve tickets from users
- Participate in Development new SAP Systems with SAP ABAP especially in Sales and Delivering Module.
- Besides, also consult to end user about how to improve system's reliability and durability such as move to the clouds and how to backup data efficiently
- Estimation project costs and deadline for new features

Luxoft Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2012/10 - 2013/10

Junior Action Script Developer (full-time)

- Develop the HEAD-UNIT (Main Control Menu) for Mercedes cars in Flash (Action Script 3.)
- Perform Unit Test to enhance the quality as well as detect potential bugs inside the system Accomplishment
 - As a junior developer in team, I learned a lot from others elite engineers from task scheduling to coding quality.
 - Working in a multinational professional engineers was a chance to enhance my English skills, and experience with multicultural environment

INTERN / PART-TIME EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2011/10 - 2012/10

 Projects of different scales involving Full Stack Development, as well as maintenance and migration old framework. Focusing mainly on .NET Technology and its ecosystems
 Accomplishments (see below, and more)

- Windows application to input Contract in Insurance Company.(VB.NET)
- Windows Application in Medical for Scanning and Detecting disease in Breast (Migration from VB6 to VB.NET)
- Renew mobile website of Airlines company (Java Struts 1)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Ask Vietnamese (https://askvietnamese.vn/home)

2017/12 - Present

Full stack developer

• This is the non-profit project that helps foreigners to understand more about my country Vietnam. I'm working as a Full stack developer as well as DevOps in this project

Nech.info (https://nech.info)

2016/10-Present

Blogger

 This is my personal blog, that I started in 2016, to write about my thoughts in software engineering.

Viet Professional Japans (https://vietpro.jp/)

2018/04-Present

Team member

 As a Vietnamese, I always want to connect with other Vietnamese professionals in Japan, so I joined the team to carry out my desire. Working as a Web Developer, I'm maintaining the site and help the team in propose new idea as well as make the site easier to use.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Associate Developer Certification Nov 2017 – Nov 2019

TOEIC L&R: 890 Sep 2017

AWS Associate Architect Certification Jun 2017 – Jun 2019

Japanese Language Profiency Test: N2 Jul 2016

Pearson Summit 2 Certification May 2013

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering Sep 2009 – May 2013

FPT University, Vietnam

LANGUAGES

Japanese: High Intermediate

English: Fluent